When we deploy a service, it's often very convenient to have access to the machine providing this service.
It can be a server or set by your cloud provider,
it can be a LoRaWAN gateway, it can be a simple Raspberry Pi.
Well, there are dozens of examples where we need to get control of the remote machine to configure
it.
If we don't have this remote access, then we need to have a physical access to this machine with a
keyboard, a mouse and a screen.
So you get that.
It's really hard to do that and sometimes impossible when this remote access is activated and we are
logged in, then we end up with a terminal where we can control the machine.
Exactly
if we were connected directly with it, obviously this remote access must be secure and the most used
protocol for a secure remote access is SSH.
Using it is very simple.
We just need an SSH client.
Mobaxterm provides such an SSH client.
So let's make an example of an SSH connection on a remote Linux server.
In MobaXterm we open a local terminal, then we just need to type SSH followed by the username on our
server.
The username is debian.
Then @, here we need to enter the server IP address or its name.
In our case the service name is test.univ-lorawan.fr
Then, we just enter the password.
And there we go.
We are logged in and we can control the server.
With MobaXterm, we can also use the graphical user interface.
We click on Session, SSH, then we enter the remote control host test.univ-lorawan.fr,
the username debian and then, same process again,
we enter the password.
Great.
So during this lecture, when we say that we use a remote SSH connection, then that's exactly what we'll
do.